Travelogues
Marist Archives and Special Collections
Travelogues
2.1.3.1.2
Marist College
  Box 1509
- Travelogues, 2.1.3.1.2
  - Travelogues: Francis Yeats-Brown (India), 1921 - 1922; 4 (Box 1509)
    - Caption: Major F. Yeats-Brown, Author of "The Lives of a Bengal Lancer" shown here in disguise as a German governess in Constantinople during the war (The Viking Press), 1
    - Caption: Major F. Yeats-Brown, Author of "The Lives of Bengal Lacer" shown here in his disguise as a German mechanic in Constantinople during the war (Viking Press), 2
    - Caption: Major F. Yeats-Brown, In full regalia as a cavalry officer in the Indian Bengal Lancers. His life in India is the subject of his newly published book, "The Lives of a Bengal Lancer" (Viking Press), 3
    - Caption: Major F. Yeats-Brown, Of the Indian Bengal Lancers standing between one of the senior officers of the Indian troops and one of the religious leaders of India. Major Yeats-Brown has just written the story of his life in "The Lives of a Bengal Lancer" (The Viking Press) [2 copies], 4
    - Caption: Major F. Yeats-Brown, (left center) with the polo team which won the Indian Cavalry and Inter-Regimental Tournaments in India in 1921. Polo I just one of the many adventures which he describes so vividly in his book "The Lives of a Bengal Lancer" (The Viking Press) [2 copies], 5
  - Travelogues: India [photographs of textual materials], 1921; 5 (Box 1509)
    - [Invitation to a luncheon from Governor Lloyd of Bombay, India to Mr. and Mrs. Lowell Thomas], 1
    - [Picture of Sultan Saheb Jangbaz Jang in The Bombay Chronicle, India], 2
    - [Announcement of Lowell Thomas showing "With Allenby in Palestine" and "Lawrence in Arabia" at Empire Theatre, Calcutta, India], 3
  - Travelogues: Royal Opera House, Covent Garden (London), circa 1919 - early 1920s; 6 (Box 1509)
    - The famous Covent Garden Opera House in London, most celebrated theatre in the English speaking world. This was at the time when L.T. was telling the story of "With Lawrence in Arabia and With Allenby in Palestine," which was heard by more than a million people in London, and by some four million people around the world, 1
    - Note: The famous Covent Garden Opera House in London, most celebrated theatre in the English speaking world. This was at the time when L.T. was telling the story of "With Lawrence in Arabia and With Allenby in Palestine," which was heard by more than a million people in London, and by some four million people around the world, 2
    - The Bishop of Gloucester, the millionth visitor to see and hear With Allenby in Palestine and Lawrence in Arabia in London, congratulating Lowell Thomas outside the Royal Opera House, Covent Gardens, where Thomas told his strange tale of adventure for nearly a year, 3
    - Verso: The Bishop of Gloucester, the millionth visitor to see and hear With Allenby in Palestine and Lawrence in Arabia in London, congratulating Lowell Thomas outside the Royal Opera House, Covent Gardens, where Thomas told his strange tale of adventure for nearly a year, 3-verso
    - Bishop 1,000,00th Visitor. The Bishop of Gloucester, Dr. Gibson, proved to be the 1,000,000th visitor to Mr. Lowell Thomas's moving picture travelogue. With Allenby in Palestine and Lawrence in Arabia" at the Queen's Hall, W., yesterday afternoon. The bishop expressed to Mr. Lowell Thomas, his great delight will the entertainment, which as stated in yesterday's Daily Mail, will close Friday. From the "Daily Mail" Jan 27th, Permission to use this photograph is given free of charge, 4
    - Verso: Bishop 1,000,00th Visitor. The Bishop of Gloucester, Dr. Gibson, proved to be the 1,000,000th visitor to Mr. Lowell Thomas's moving picture travelogue. With Allenby in Palestine and Lawrence in Arabia" at the Queen's Hall, W., yesterday afternoon. The bishop expressed to Mr. Lowell Thomas, his great delight will the entertainment, which as stated in yesterday's Daily Mail, will close Friday. From the "Daily Mail" Jan 27th, Permission to use this photograph is given free of charge, 4-verso
    - In London, Lowell Thomas the American explorer and lecturer was heard by more than one million people who came to see him at the Royal Opera House. He is the most famous lecturer in the world today although still in his early thirties. Permission to use this photograph is given free of charge., 5
    - Verso: In London, Lowell Thomas the American explorer and lecturer was heard by more than one million people who came to see him at the Royal Opera House. He is the most famous lecturer in the world today although still in his early thirties. Permission to use this photograph is given free of charge., 5-verso
    - Bishop 1,000,00th Visitor. The Bishop of Gloucester, Dr. Gibson, proved to be the 1,000,000th visitor to Mr. Lowell Thomas's moving picture travelogue. With Allenby in Palestine and Lawrence in Arabia" at the Queen's Hall, W., yesterday afternoon. The bishop expressed to Mr. Lowell Thomas, his great delight will the entertainment, which as stated in yesterday's Daily Mail, will close Friday. From the "Daily Mail" Jan 27th, Permission to use this photograph is given free of charge, 6
    - Verso: Bishop 1,000,00th Visitor. The Bishop of Gloucester, Dr. Gibson, proved to be the 1,000,000th visitor to Mr. Lowell Thomas's moving picture travelogue. With Allenby in Palestine and Lawrence in Arabia" at the Queen's Hall, W., yesterday afternoon. The bishop expressed to Mr. Lowell Thomas, his great delight will the entertainment, which as stated in yesterday's Daily Mail, will close Friday. From the "Daily Mail" Jan 27th, Permission to use this photograph is given free of charge, 6-verso
    - Bishop of Gloucester, Dr. Gibson, the one millionth to hear L.T. in London - with his Allenby-Lawrence [2 copies], 7
    - Verso: Bishop of Gloucester, Dr. Gibson, the one millionth to hear L.T. in London - with his Allenby-Lawrence, 7-verso
  - Travelogues: Theater billboards, circa 1919 - early 1920s; 7 (Box 1509)
    - L.T. and Fran next to "With Allenby in Palestine" and "From Cairo to Mecca" billboard, 1
    - "Through Romantic India" billboard, 2
    - "Through Romantic India" billboard, 3
    - "Through Romantic India" billboard, 4
  - Travelogues: Travelogue photographs for Jerusalem article by Lowell Thomas, circa 1918 - early 1920s; 8 (Box 1509)
    - Some of Allenby's French troops on guard before the Church of the Holy Sepulchre. Lowell Thomas, 1
    - Verso: Some of Allenby's French troops on guard before the Church of the Holy Sepulchre. Lowell Thomas, 1-verso
    - Jerusalem from the Mt. of Olive Masque of Omar occupying site of Soloman's Temple, in the fore ground. Lowell Thomas, 2
    - Verso: Jerusalem from the Mt. of Olive Masque of Omar occupying site of Soloman's Temple, in the fore ground. Lowell Thomas, 2-verso
    - Jerusalem from Garden of Gethsemanee, 3
    - Verso: Jerusalem from Garden of Gethsemanee, 3-verso
    - Mosque of Omar + Jerusalem from Mt. of Olives, 4
    - Verso: Mosque of Omar + Jerusalem from Mt. of Olives, 4-verso
    - Veiled woman in Jerusalem, 5
    - Verso: Veiled woman in Jerusalem, 5-verso
    - Hardboiled Smith V.C., Commander of the Imperial Camel Corps, 6
    - Verso: "Hardboiled" Smith V.C., Commander of the Imperial Camel Corps, 6-verso
    - Maj. Seward, on left, who swam 17 miles when his plane crashed in the Mediterranean., 7
    - Verso: Maj. Seward, on left, who swam 17 miles when his plane crashed in the Mediterranean., 7-verso
    - The eastern wall of Jerusalem, 8
    - Verso: The eastern wall of Jerusalem, 8-verso
    - Moslem girl of Palestine, 9
    - Verso: Moslem girl of Palestine, 9-verso
    - An Arab school, 10
    - Verso: An Arab school, 10-verso
    - Sir Philip [Chetwode] who led the army corps that captured Jerusalem. His staff + L.T. on Mt. of Olives, 11
    - Verso: Sir Philip [Chetwode] who led the army corps that captured Jerusalem. His staff + L.T. on Mt. of Olives, 11-verso
    - In the Court of the Mosque of Omar. Lowell Thomas, 12
    - Verso: In the Court of the Mosque of Omar. Lowell Thomas, 12-verso
    - Fourth Station of the Cross, on the Via Dolorosa. Lowell Thomas, 13
    - Verso: Fourth Station of the Cross, on the Via Dolorosa. Lowell Thomas, 13-verso
    - Mosque of Omar, Indian on guard, 14
    - Verso: 2-118 [Mosque of Omar, Indian on guard], 14-verso
    - Mosque, of Omar and Jerusalem. Greek church in foreground, 15
    - Verso: P2-121 [Mosque, of Omar and Jerusalem. Greek church in foreground], 15-verso
    - Golden Gate, 16
    - Verso: P2-135 ["Golden Gate"], 16-verso
    - Jerusalem from Mount of Olives, spires of Russian church in foreground, 17
    - Verso: P2-136 [Jerusalem from Mount of Olives, spires of Russian church in foreground], 17-verso
    - British soldier on guard at Mount of Olives, large tree in foreground, 18
    - Verso: 2-355 [British soldier on guard at Mount of Olives, large tree in foreground], 18-verso
    - Map of Palestine and Syria, 19
    - Note: These go with Thomas' Jerusalem article, D., 20
  - Travelogues: Frank R. Roberson, circa late 1800s - 1916; 9 (Box 1509)
    - [Balcony looking [?] with Balcony Home Mesa Verde Nat'l Park Colo. ], 1
    - Verso: Balcony looking [?] with Balcony Home Mesa Verde Nat'l Park Colo., 1-verso
    - Caption: Picture Writing Yellow Jacket Canon, Colo., 2
    - [Aztec Mummies Mesa Verde National Park Colo. ], 3
    - Verso: Aztec Mummies M.V. Nat'l Park Colo., 3-verso
    - [Cliff Palace, Mesa Verde Nat'l Park Colorado], 4
    - Verso: Cliff Palace, Mesa Verde Nat'l Park Colorado, 4-verso
    - [Balcony (?) House Mesa Verde National Park Colorado], 5
    - Verso: Balcony [?] House Mesa Verde Nat'l Park Colorado, 5-verso
    - [Balcony Home Mesa Verde National Park Colorado Reached via (?) + Riogrande R.R.], 6
    - Verso: Balcony Home Mesa Verde Nat'l Park Colorado Reached via [?] + Riogrande R.R., 6-verso
    - [Spurce Tree Home Mesa Verde National Park Colorado (looking north)], 7
    - Verso: Spurce Tree Home Mesa Verde Nat'l Park Colorado (looking north), 7-verso
    - [Panorama of Cliff Palace, Mesa Verde National Park, Colorado], 8
    - Caption: North End Cliff Palace Mesa Verde Nat'l Park, 9
    - Caption: Round Tower and Mesa Building Ruin Canon Utah, 10
    - [Wall of bricks with two caverns, steps leading into one], 11
    - [Holland, Amsterdam Railroad Station], 12
    - Verso: Holland, Amsterdam Railroad Station, 12-verso
    - [Holland, The Hague Houses showing various styles and architecture], 13
    - Verso: Holland, The Hague Houses showing various styles and architecture, 13-verso
    - [Sorrento], 14
    - Verso: Sorrento, 14-verso
    - [Italy, Genoa], 15
    - Verso: Italy, Genoa, 15-verso
    - [Sicily-Garden at Loarmina (Toarmina?)], 16
    - Verso: Sicily-Garden at Loarmina [Toarmina?], 16-verso
    - [Maderia-Sea Shore], 17
    - Verso: Maderia-Sea Shore, 17-verso
    - [Maderia - Town from old Fort], 18
    - Verso: Maderia - Town from old Fort, 18-verso
    - [Sweden, Stockholm Strandr gen(?) Fine Houses], 19
    - Verso: Sweden, Stockholm Strandr gen[?] Fine Houses, 19-verso
    - [Sweden, Stockholm Blasiehhamner(?)], 20
    - Verso: Sweden, Stockholm Blasiehhamner[?], 20-verso
    - [Sweden, Stockholm Boat Market + Water Front], 21
    - Verso: Sweden, Stockholm Boat Market + Water Front, 21-verso
    - [Sweden - Stockholm Royal Palace], 22
    - Verso: Sweden - Stockholm Royal Palace, 22-verso
    - [Sweden - Stockholm ], 23
    - Verso: Sweden - Stockholm, 23-verso
    - [Sweden Locks at Akersrasl(?)], 24
    - Verso: Sweden Locks at Akersrasl[?], 24-verso
    - [Sweden - Stockholm Outlet to the Baltic.], 25
    - Verso: Sweden - Stockholm Outlet to the Baltic., 25-verso
    - [Houses on the other side of a river], 26
    - [Pottery], 27
    - Verso: Pottery, 27-verso
    - [Group of people sitting on the deck of a boat], 28
    - [Man looking at the camera, half smiling], 29
    - [Natural rock bridge covered in snow, trees below], 30
    - [Natural rock bridge, people walking across], 31
    - [Cliff Palace Tiva(?)], 32
    - Verso: Cliff Palace Tiva[?], 32-verso
  - Travelogues: Frank R. Roberson, circa late 1800s - 1916; 10 (Box 1509)
    - [Holland - Amsterdam Binnen Amstel, Sophia Plein(?)], 1
    - Verso: Holland - Amsterdam Binnen Amstel, Sophia Plein[?], 1-verso
    - [Damascus, Syria], 2
    - Verso: Damascus, Syria, 2-verso
    - [Holland Amsterdam Jewish Quarter.], 3
    - Verso: Holland Amsterdam Jewish Quarter., 3-verso
    - [Holland - The Hague Canal Scene], 4
    - Verso: Holland - The Hague Canal Scene, 4-verso
    - [Holland - Dardrecht - Canal Bit], 5
    - Verso: Holland - Dardrecht - Canal Bit, 5-verso
    - [Holland, Dardrecht Up a Canal], 6
    - Verso: Holland, Dardrecht Up a Canal, 6-verso
    - [Holland, Rotterdam Isroote(?) Kerk, or Church of St. Lawrence and R.R. Bridge], 7
    - Verso: Holland, Rotterdam Isroote[?] Kerk, or Church of St. Lawrence and R.R. Bridge, 7-verso
    - [Holland, Rotterdam In the Business Section], 8
    - Verso: Holland, Rotterdam In the Business Section, 8-verso
    - [Holland, Rotterdam The Boompjes[?]], 9
    - Verso: Holland, Rotterdam The Boompjes[?], 9-verso
    - [Mildred and Thorburg shaking hands, Norway], 10
    - Verso: Mildred and Thorburg shaking hands, Norway, 10-verso
    - [Colonel Goethal's private car Panama], 11
    - Verso: Colonel Goethal's private car Panama, 11-verso
    - [Chief Officer Gronow S.S. Corona], 12
    - Verso: Chief Officer Gronow S.S. Corona, 12-verso
    - [Captain Barr in Cabin S.S. Corona], 13
    - Verso: Captain Barr in Cabin S.S. Corona, 13-verso
    - [Frank Roberson on Bridge S.S. Corona], 14
    - Verso: Frank Roberson on Bridge S.S. Corona, 14-verso
    - [Hope Gardens, Jamaica], 15
    - Verso: Hope Gardens, Jamaica, 15-verso
    - [Bedouin Children at Busta - Petra], 16
    - Verso: Bedouin Children at Busta - Petra, 16-verso
  - Travelogues Lowell Thomas in Arab headdress, circa early 1920s; 11 (Box 1509)
    - [autographed by Lowell Thomas: "With best wishes for a long life crammed with high adventure. Lowell Thomas"] [16 copies], 1